

# **KATHLEEN MOLONY**

FRENCH TEACHER

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I'm a 6-12 experienced world language educator who actively follows best practices for language acquisition. I excel at incorporating technology to aid in my students learning in both the traditional and virtual classroom. In my free time, I am a co-founder and admin of Forsyth Educator Advocacy Forum, a local group of educators who work to support all those involved in public education in Forsyth County, NC and surrounding areas.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

NC Professional Educator's License, 2020 Standard Professional License, Highly Qualified

- French Grades K-12
- Latin Grades 9-12
- Anthropology Grades 9-12

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**

336-686-6208 k8molony@att.net LinkedIn: @k8molony



# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **FRENCH TEACHER**

Walter Hines Page High School August 2019 - present

- Sole French teacher with levels 1,2,3,4 and IB
- Led PD sessions on technology for the entire staff
- Exclusively online from March 2020 to present

Paisley IB Middle School August 2015 - August 2019

-Department Chair of both Foreign Language and all of Encore

Southeast Middle School (Guilford County) August 2014 - August 2015

Southeast Middle School (Forsyth County) August 2012 - August 2014

- Received Jaguar Award for most promising first year teacher

#### FIELD INTERVIEWER

National Opinion Research Center April 2008 - January 2014

- Administered carefully developed, field-tested questionnaires to respondents.
- Maintained professional data collection and anonymity standards
- Working remotely, reported project status through weekly calls to a Field Manager

#### SENIOR SUPPORT ANALYST

Ace Hardware Corporation September 1999 - July 2005

- -Trained retailers as well as coworkers on in house ERP
- Provided tech support primarily over the phone but also in person
- Worked remotely from home from January 2004 until July 2005

#### ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

#### UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA. GREENSBORO

Post-Baccalaureate Certificate, Class of 2011

- NCTEACH, French, grades K-12

B.A. Classical Studies, Class of 2006

- Chancellor's List
- Dean's List

#### UNIVERSITY OF NEW MEXICO

B.A. Anthropology, Class of 1997

#### **SKILLS AND ABILITIES**

- Teaching French using CI/TPRS practices
- Using data to support creative lesson planning
- Integrating technology to supplement learning, including programs such as Canvas, Nearpod, Peardeck, EdPuzzle, Padlet, Quizizz, Gimkit, and Blooket, as well as Google and Microsoft Office suites.
- Established a successful organizational system to juggle the necessary planning and prep for 5 levels of French simultaneously.